MATTHEW WIGHT

(+44)7804814652 • matthew.wight47@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/mattheww02 • mattheww02.github.io/mwapp

SUMMARY

Recently graduated Computer Science Master's student keen to be challenged and make an impact in the field of software development. Conscientious, hard-working and enthusiastic with an excellent academic record and several periods of experience working and volunteering in a wide variety of roles. Relevant experience with software engineering, project management, computer networks, machine learning and full stack development.

EDUCATION

Undergraduate Degree

2020 - 2024 University of Warwick

2018 - 2020 Stretford Grammar School

MEng Computer Science, 2:1 (68%)

Modules include: Software Engineering, Project Management, Database Systems, Algorithms, Operating Systems

A Level

Mathematics: A* Physics: A* Computer Science: A*

PROJECTS

Online Chat and Drawing App (Personal Project)

2024

- Built an online real-time whiteboard drawing and chat app with C# ASP.NET, React (TypeScript) and Bootstrap CSS.
- Implemented user profiles, concurrent rooms and live collaboration through a combination of websockets and APIs.

Chess Engine (Personal Project)

2024

- Built a chess-playing AI with estimated Elo rating of 2000 using Java, with Maven for build management.
- Integrated with a flexible custom-built interface, allowing for both human and Al opponents.

Automated Image Geolocation OSINT (Master's Group Project)

2023 - 2024

- Worked as a team to design and implement an automated system to gather intelligence from images via deep learning and computer vision to achieve state-of-the-art performance on image geolocation tasks.
- Created a robust desktop app with intuitive interface and efficient back end to improve workflow for both intelligence experts and casual users.
- Utilised tech stack of Electron, Python/Django, SQLite, JavaScript/ReactJS, Bootstrap CSS and HTML as well as APIs from Google Cloud Platform and Azure. Implemented automated unit tests with Pytest.

Sentiment Analysis of Political News Articles (Undergraduate Dissertation)

2022 - 2023

- Utilised ML tools including Scikit-learn, TensorFlow and Keras to build an autoencoder-based deep learning model that would predict sentiment expressed in news articles, achieving an accuracy of 95%.
- Used data visualisation tools including Tableau and MatPlotLib to provide insight.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: Python, Java, C, C++, C#, JavaScript, TypeScript, Bash, SQL, Haskell, MATLAB, HTML

Software Engineering: agile, lean, test-driven development, CI/CD, OOP, project management, PRINCE2 & waterfall

Frameworks, DevOps & Cloud: React, Django, .NET, Git (Github), Docker, Jira, Azure, AWS, GCP

EXPERIENCE

Department of Computer Science, University of Warwick: Graduate Teaching Assistant September 2023 - June 2024

- Taught students in use of Linux systems, Bash scripting, writing technical documents and Haskell programming
- Assisted with the delivery of lab sessions and provided feedback and guidance to students

Cove, Didsbury, Manchester: Bartender

Summer 2022

Took food and drinks orders from customers and prepared drinks in a restaurant with bar

Ark Nightclub, Deansgate, Manchester: Bartender

Summer 2021

Prepared drinks orders for customers and cleaned venue during and after opening hours

Pet's Corner, Chorlton, Manchester: Volunteer

October 2018 - November 2019

Cared for various animals including goats, chickens, ducks, rabbits and hares

AWARDS AND ACTIVITIES

- UKMT Mathematical Challenge Gold Award at Junior and Intermediate levels
- Stretford Grammar Sixth Form Certificates for Outstanding Achievement in Computer Science, Physics
- Stretford Grammar Sixth Form Certificates for Outstanding Effort in Computer Science, Mathematics
- Duke of Edinburgh Gold Award (pending, all sections completed)